JIA-LIN BRASWELL

GIS Specialist

INFO



Address

444 Del Sol Avenue, Pleasanton, CA



Phone

925 768 9733



Email

gpsguru1989@gmail.com



Github

jbraswell-gpsguru.github.io

EDUCATION

Masters in GIS/Cartography and Web Map Development

University of Wisconsin Madison / Aug 2017 - Dec 2019

Bachelor of Arts in Geography

University of California
Berkeley / Aug 2012 - May 2014

Architecture/Geography

Diablo Valley College Pleasant Hill, CA / Aug 2008 -May 2012

TRAINING

GIS

City College of San Francisco Nov 2014 - Present

Coding

General Assembly / San Francisco May 2016 - Present

SUMMARY

Organized, versatile and reliable GIS technician with 9 years experience who excels in managing multiple tasks, in scheduling people and resources, and in prioritizing competing responsibilities. Analyze Geographic Information Systems (GIS) data for use in urban planning applications that promote better land use or reduce the environmental impacts of development. Elite-level support skills, including the ability to manage a high volume of data, able to tailor communication to all levels of the organization.

EXPERIENCE

GIS Consultant

G2 Integrated Solutions - Entrust/ December 2021 - Present

- Consultant with Pacific Gas & Electric (PG&E) assisting the Natural Resource Management
 Team in modifying maps, data, and Quality Control (QC) Work.
- Collaborate with PG&E Technicians and Land Planners on the field that collect data when updating road segments on maps in ESRI and producing QC Error Reports.
- Updating procedures for daily tasks completed.
- Process KMZ requests for Land Planners and Technicians that map out the location of roads, gates, transmission lines, and poles.

GIS Technician

Disclosure Source - Fidelity National / December 2014 - December 2021

- Create and manage data and maps combined with geographically referenced data.
- Update map data using a digitizer or by direct input of coordinate information using the
 principles of cartography including coordinate systems, longitude, latitude, elevation,
 topography, and map scales.
- Analyze Geographic Information Systems (GIS) data to identify spatial relationships or display results of analyses.
- Apply data in transportation routing settings to determine the best routing to reduce pollution and energy consumption.

Driver

Uber / July 2014 - December 2016

 Drive vehicles over specified routes or to specified destinations according to time schedules, complying with traffic regulations to ensure that passengers have a smooth and safe ride.

Intern

Greenbelt Alliance / August 2014 - October 2014

 Responsible for providing policy research and geographic information systems support for open space protection and better city planning in the San Francisco Bay Area.

EXPERTISE

- GIS technology and integrations/dependencies
- GIS & Spatial Analysis
- Identifies key issues in complex situations
- Sets challenging, achievable goals
- Expands and uses professional knowledge
- Up-to-date with emerging practices

COURSES

- Geospatial Web & Mobile Programming
- GIS & Spatial Analysis
- GIS Quick Start
- Vectors and Rasters
- Python for ArcGIS
- Open Source Geostack

SKILLS

- Software: ARCGIS; Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Illustrator, QGIS, Leaflet, Python, ArcPro
- Languages: Proficient in Mandarin Chinese, and American Sign Language

PROJECTS

Mapping Oakland's Check/Cashing Providers and Banks

Used Google Maps and City of Oakland data to create a detailed map in order to show the locations of these services along International Boulevard.

Mapping San Francisco's Art Deco buildings

Combined data from libraries and the San Francisco City Assessment website to Map out the famous Art Deco structures in San Francisco. Designed a user-friendly map to pinpoint the locations of these structures using both ARCGIS and Adobe Illustrator.

522 Mission Street San Francisco Urban Planning Project

Proposed to construct a mixed-use high rise of an open site in San Francisco. Incorporated into the project the ideas of SB 375, AB 32, and TOD, with the main focus of encouraging people to take transit, walk, bike, as alternatives to driving.

Determining Optimum Locations for Retail Sites in San Francisco

Collaborated with a teammate to develop a plan for retail expansion in the City of San Francisco, taking into account existing geographical considerations.

Revitalizing the Diablo Valley College Lake

Led a group of three students in designing conceptual diagrams and planned an area with the consideration of land use and pedestrian traffic.

San Francisco Cable Car System Then & Now

Implemented an Interactive online mapping application using ESRI Leaflet and HTML Brackets that displays a map of the routes of the cable car system in San Francisco, also, chronicles the history of the cable car system from how the system started, the fight to save the system, and the system today.